Matthew Matterson
151 Camberton Road
Leighton Buzzard
Bedfordshire
LU72UW
07957362245

mattersonis@gmail.com 11<sup>th</sup> November 1991

Portfolio site: www.mytimelearning.co.uk

## Available for positions as an Intern or Junior Web Developer

### **Summary:**

I started my professional working life five years ago in the Recruitment Industry. Spending three years with two small companies before moving on, in 2014, to start my own independent consultancy named Fairbeck.

Several months later a friend and I began developing a new business idea for an online recruitment platform. I used my consultancy as a way of financing the new venture and eventually merging the two. That took us through 2015, but unfortunately the business didn't work out as we'd hoped and we've now shut down.

The silver lining from this endeavour has been my introduction to the world of Web Development.

### Why web development?

It all began so that I could understand the technical aspects and support my business partner with the more basic duties, such as managing the user database and posting blogs.

It soon became a genuine interest and I began spending all the time I could to learn and, eventually, dabble inside our websites code for practical experience.

When the business began to show signs of failing, that loss was balanced by the possibility of finally having found a career path that I enjoy. My efforts are now focused towards ensuring I successfully break into a career as a Web Developer.

I still have a lot to learn, however, if a business is willing to help me develop I will return that investment with dedication, loyalty and a great work ethic.

### Work history:

# December 2014 – March 2016 Enhouse Limited, Director & Co-Founder / Junior Web Developer

Enhouse was an Online Staffing Platform that would enable Freelance Engineers to work directly with Employers.

My primary duty as Director was to manage all the business aspects covering tax, invoicing, business development, marketing, web site content writing, website design and account management.

It was during my time running Enhouse that I began learning how to code.

# Responsibilities as a Web Developer:

Our site is built with the Symfony2 framework using HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Javascript, MySQL and Php.

Having access to an advanced platform has been a fantastic learning opportunity to develop my skills by making real world modifications.

Some of my responsibilities and tasks include:

- Design and build wire frames outlining the Websites entire desired functionality
- Redesigning and maintaining the front page content and layout
- Develop the internal user notifications & messages
- Posting regular blog updates directly to the site through the database
- Managing a large database of users and monitoring activity
- Publishing and committing changes to the AWS server (GitGui)
- Building the 'Contact Us' form
- Debug, examine and test the code and functions

#### May 2014 - May 2015

### Fairbeck Technical Resources Ltd, Director (London)

I established Fairbeck as a way of self-financing a new business idea – Enhouse.

My position was that of an independent recruiter. I worked with engineering organisations to find and place individuals.

Fairbeck was eventually merged with Enhouse to form one company.

## June 2012 - May 2014

Secondsite Recruitment Ltd, Recruitment Consultant

# June 2011 - August 2012

**Entech Technical Solutions, Recruitment Consultant** 

#### **Education:**

### Learning to become a Web Developer:

8 months ago I could hardly read simple HTML code.

After consistently putting in between 1 & 2 hours every day, plus several more each weekend. I now have enough knowledge to read, understand, modify and write a websites code. To reach this point I completed several online workshops.

- CodeCademy A fantastic learning platform that provides beginners with easy to follow lessons and projects to start out. I completing the following courses: HTML & CSS, Javascript, Php, JQuery, Git and SQL.
- Udemy: The Complete Web Developers Course This intensive online course consisted of 28 hours of lectures and covered HTML, JS, CSS, PHP, MySQL, Bootstrap, JQuery, Wordpress and APIs.
- KNP University Before I could modify our websites code I needed to learn the framework.
  KNP provides much admired courses for Symfony2, PHP, RESTful API's and Object
  Orientated Programming. Each course is designed to help the pupil work alongside the video and built an app/website from scratch.
- Laracasts Laracast provides an in-depth web tutorial for learning the Laravel framework. The Laravel path contains ten steps including almost 20 hours worth of instructional lessons from initial introduction through to intermediate and project creation.

# HarvardX: CS50 Introduction to Computer Science (2015 - Present)

Introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming. This course teaches students how to think algorithmically and solve problems efficiently. Topics include abstraction, algorithms, data structures, encapsulation, resource management, security, software engineering, and web development. Languages include C, PHP, and JavaScript plus SQL, CSS, and HTML. Problem sets inspired by real-world domains of biology, cryptography, finance, forensics, and gaming.

# A-Levels, Cedars Sixth Form College

- Maths C
- Design Technology D
- History D

## GCSE, Cedars Upper School

• 9 C grade or above

Interests: Politics, Current & World affairs, History, Economics and Business

Hobbies: Bouldering, Running, Gym, Reading, Films and Television.

### References:

Available on request